Main Menu

Web Privacy Policy
==================

[Home](https://www.midlandcredit.com/) Web Privacy Policy

Last Updated July 7, 2023

Effective Date: October 19, 2022

The Web Privacy Policy outlined below is applicable to information you submit to our web site at [www.midlandcredit.com](https://www.midlandcredit.com/) or [https://mcmpay.com/](https://mcmpay.com/) (collectively, the “Site”). It does not apply to information collected from other sources, including off-line information collection. For general information related to our collection and use of personally identifiable information from any source, including the Site, please see our [Privacy Notice](https://www.midlandcredit.com/privacy-policy-and-state-disclosures/).

We may change this Web Privacy Policy from time to time. The “Effective Date” legend at the top of the page indicates when this Web Privacy Policy was last revised.

**Information We Collect**

MCM respects your right to privacy, and your right to be free from unwanted Internet intrusions. When a visitor contacts the Site, we may collect personal identifying information such as name, street and e-mail addresses, phone numbers, the site the visitor linked from, and other information which, when used by itself or with other data, might identify that person (“Personally Identifiable Information”). We typically collect Information from these sources:

**Automatic Information.** We receive and store some Information automatically when you interact with the Site, such as information your web browser provides to our web server. Like many websites, we use “cookies,” which are unique identifiers that we transfer to your device to enable us to recognize your device and to provide certain features to you. For example, we may use Marketing Munchkin Tracking cookies to track behavior of certain consumers who visit our website and may use Marketo cookies from our third-party email provider to track whether our emails are opened and to track certain activity on the Site. More information on Marketo’s privacy and cookie policy can be found at [https://www.marketo.com/company/legal/](https://www.marketo.com/company/legal/).

If you prefer that we do not place cookies on your web browser you may opt out by clicking the Do Not Track (DNT) feature in your browser. This prevents tracking for your particular browser and device. The Help feature on most browsers will also tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Because cookies enable you to use certain features on the Site, we recommend that you leave them turned on.

**Third Party Analytics Providers .** We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit, when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site on your browser.

We also use FullStory’s session recording services to better understand how MCM’s visitors use the Site and to optimize the functionality of our site for the best user experience. We record and/or monitor your use of the Site, such as pages visited, links clicked, text entered, and mouse movements, as well as information more commonly collected such as the referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider. We also collect potentially personally identifying information like Internet Protocol (or “IP”) addresses. Also, you may choose to interact with the Site in a manner that results in your providing, and our recording the entry of, other personally-identifiable information such as your name, email address, password, financial account details, and other sensitive information. MCM does not use information recorded via its usage of FullStory to identify its visitors and does not use such information other than under the circumstances described in this Web Privacy Policy or MCM’s Privacy Notice. By using the Site, you are aware and consent to our recording of your information and activity on our Site for the purposes described herein. If you prefer that we do not record your web sessions, you may opt out here: [https://www.fullstory.com/optout/#](https://www.fullstory.com/optout/)

**Ad Partners.** We use search and display networks, such as Google Ads and Microsoft’s Bing to reach consumers. These platforms allow us to communicate with consumers using tools such as standard and custom affinity audiences, in-market audiences, and demographic and location targeting. They also allow us to monitor the performance of our ads through conversion tracking. None of the information utilized or collected in these practices is Personally Identifiable Information. We also use the remarketing features in platforms such as GoogleAds to reach specific audiences. Google and others utilize cookies to display customized ads to customers who have previously visited this website . If you prefer, you may opt out of Google’s use of cookies for advertising, including DoubleClick cookies, at any time by visiting Google’s Ad Settings page at [https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en).

We also use display networks such as DV360 and Criteo to reach our consumers. When you visit the Site, we may utilize cookies that help us better understand your browsing behavior using our Site. None of the information utilized or collected in these practices is Personally Identifiable Information. If you prefer not to receive these ads, you may opt out at any time by visiting [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/) or visit [https://www.criteo.com/privacy/disable-criteo-services-on-internet-browsers/](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/disable-criteo-services-on-internet-browsers/).

We may also use social media sites such as Facebook to retarget ads to MCM consumers. You can opt out of the type of ads you see on Facebook by visiting [https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217/](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217/).

**E-mail Messages.** We receive and store information you provide to us through electronic mail (“e-mail”) communications to us. Additionally, to help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we may receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from the Site if your computer supports such capabilities. We also use third-party marketing software from Marketo to send our emails.

**Mobile.** When you download or use apps created by or for MCM or the Site, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as marketing, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services.

**Information you provide to us.** We receive and store information you enter on the Site, for example, when you complete a search request, or voluntarily provide information in any other way on the Site. If you prefer that we not collect and store information that you provide to us about you on the Site, please do not provide it to us and do not access the Site.

**How We Use Your Information**

Midland Credit Management, Inc. (“MCM,” “We,” or “Us”) is a debt collector and our communications are an attempt to collect debt. Any information obtained may be used for that purpose. MCM will use and share Information that you provide through the Site for the specific purpose for which you submitted the Information and/or as described in this Web Privacy Policy, in accordance with our Privacy Notice, and to assemble Information we obtain to assess the usefulness and popularity of the various web pages on our Site, or certain links to or from the Site.

**Information We Share with Third Parties**

MCM may share certain information as set forth in our [Privacy Notice](https://www.midlandcredit.com/privacy-policy-and-state-disclosures/).

**Security**

We are committed to providing reasonable measures to protect your Information from any unauthorized access or disclosure and use measures to protect your information. However, no web site is invulnerable, and you should also take sensible measures to safeguard your Information. We (like all websites) cannot warrant or guarantee 100% security of any information you transmit to us through the Site.

**Your Choices About Your Personally Identifiable Information**

* **Managing “Do Not Track” Signals.** Some browsers have a Do Not Track (“DNT”) feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want your online activities tracked. When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, ad networks, plug-in providers, and other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity via cookies or other tracking technologies. MCM’s Site does not currently respond to DNT browser signals or mechanisms.
* **Protections for Children.** The Site is not designed for or targeted to children under the age of 18. MCM will never knowingly solicit or collect Personally Identifiable Information from a child under the age of 18 through the Site. If we discover that a child under the age of 18 has submitted Personally Identifiable Information, we will delete that information.
* **Commercial Electronic Communications.** If you do not wish to receive electronic communications from us, you may opt-out of receiving future electronic communications by clicking the unsubscribe link featured in our emails, contacting us at the phone number at the bottom of the page, or changing your setting in your online account at mcmpay.com.
* **Push Messages.** As part of your use of the Site, you may receive push notifications or other types of messages directly sent to you outside or inside the Site (collectively, “Push Messages”). You may control the Push Messages in your device’s settings. Some of the Push Messages may be related to your location or to your use of the Site or its content. Your carrier may charge standard messaging, data and other fees for use of Push Messages, and these fees may appear on your mobile bill or be deducted from your pre-paid balance. Your carrier may prohibit or restrict certain Push Messages and certain Push Messages may be incompatible with your carrier or mobile device. Contact your carrier with questions regarding these issues. You may discontinue Push Messages in your device’s settings. We may collect information related to your use of Push Messages. By visiting the Site and agreeing to receive any Push Messages, you agree that you own and control your device, that your device is kept in a private location, and that third parties do not have access to view any Push Messages that you may receive on that device.

**Links**

The Site may contain links to other websites. MCM has no control over and assumes no responsibility for the privacy practices of such other websites.

**Must be Eighteen (18) Years of Age**

The Site is only intended for use by adults. If you are under 18, you may use the Site only with the permission and involvement of a parent or legal guardian.

**English Version Prevails**

In the event, this Web Privacy Policy is translated into other languages and there is a discrepancy between the two language versions, the English language version shall prevail.

**DISCLAIMER**

The Site is provided for information purposes only, and the information contained herein must not be relied on as credit or legal advice. The information contained in this Site is provided only as general information. Because it is only updated periodically, such information may or may not reflect the most current information available to MCM; we cannot guarantee that it is correct or complete at any particular time. Further, MCM has no control over and does not guarantee the accuracy of information available through any links contained in this Site.

Visitors to this Site should not: (1) assume that information contained in this web site is up to date; (2) rely upon any such information for any purpose without first seeking independent advice; and (3) provide any information to MCM through this Site if the provider considers the information confidential, as this Site may not be secure. Your providing information to MCM or the Site does not create or result in any relationship between us and you, whether as credit advisor-consumer, attorney-client or otherwise. Nothing contained in this Site should be construed to constitute a recommendation or endorsement of any product, service or site by MCM.

**Contacting Us**

If you have questions or comments about this Web Privacy Policy, please contact us at the phone number at the bottom of the page.

**Changes to Our Web Privacy Policy**

The Effective Date of this Web Privacy Policy is set forth at the top of this Web Privacy Policy. MCM may from time to time make changes to this Web Privacy Policy to reflect changes in legal or regulatory obligations or changes in the manner in which we collect and use Personally Identifiable Information. We will notify you by posting the modified Web Privacy Policy, and its effective date, on this page. For this reason, you should regularly review this Web Privacy Policy and note the effective date. Your continued use of the Site after the Effective Date constitutes your acceptance of the amended Web Privacy Policy. The amended Web Privacy Policy supersedes all previous versions.

Testimonials
------------

### What People Are Saying

#### We help consumers resolve past-due debts. Hear what some of our consumers say about their experience working with MCM.

He took the time to, not only tell me about the detail of the account, but he actually listened when I said that I needed to ask a more poignant question.

–  J. B._–_  

Very accommodating, very compassionate and understanding. \[The representative I spoke with\] listened to me and tried to help me as best as possible and I really appreciate it. He had outstanding customer service.

–  K. F._–_  

Excellent customer service, very thorough and very patient with making sure that I understood the answer to my question.

–  V. M._–_  

I don't think I would change anything. My call was answered in a timely manner and the representative was very courteous and he looked into my problem, he spoke to me very nice and I really appreciate that.

–  T. S._–_  

The representative really seemed to listen, he was also proactive in his suggestions or solutions.

–  J. L._–_  

She was very professional, very nice, listened to my problem and solved it.

–  S. B._–_  

Knowledgeable and willing to go above and beyond to help me.

–  W. S._–_  

They were willing to help me as quickly as possible, and assured me that it would be done and taken care of.

–  L. R._–_  

Very helpful, organized and attentive.

–  D. B._–_  

Watch Our Testimonials Video

Reviews from Google
-------------------

### Don't Just Take Our Word for It

4.4 2599 Reviews

#### Discover what real consumers have to say about MCM

Accreditations
--------------

### MCM works with trusted partners to ensure the highest standards of quality and service.

ACA International and its design are trademarks owned by ACA International.  
DigiCert is a trademark of DigiCert, Inc. and is protected under the laws of the United States and possibly other countries.

### The Industry's First

Consumer Bill of Rights
-----------------------

Detailing our commitment to conduct business ethically and in ways that support our consumers’ financial recovery.

### Midland Credit Management

#### Need Assistance? Call Us at [(800) 296-2657](tel:800-296-2657)

_Tambien hablamos español_

We'll work with you to find a solution that works best for you.

P.O. Box 939069  
San Diego, California 92193  
NMLS ID: 934164

© Midland Credit Management, Inc. All Rights Reserved.

Encore Capital Group is a Certified Professional Receivables Company (C1312-1009 (3)) and includes a family of companies: Atlantic Credit and Finance, Midland Funding, and Midland Credit Management.

\*Please understand that this is a communication from a debt collector. This is an attempt to collect a debt. Any information obtained will be used for that purpose.

Look Up Your Account
--------------------

This form has three steps. Enter your MCM account number, then the last four digits of your social security number, and then click "Sign In".

1. MCM Account Number  MCM Account Number is required and must be between 2 to 17 digits in length.
2. Last Four Digits of SSN  The last four digits of your SSN are required.
3.  _Remember my **MCM Account Number**_

Sign In

Secure SSL Encryption

This form has four steps. Enter your last name, then provide the 2-digit month and 4-digit year of your birth, then the last four digits of your social security number, and then click "Sign In".

1. Last Name  Your last name is required.
2. Da‌te of Bi‌rth (M‌M/YY‌YY)  Your birth month and year are required.
3. Last Four Digits of SSN  The last four digits of your SSN are required.

Sign In

Secure SSL Encryption

By clicking "Continue", you acknowledge that you have read and agree to the [Terms of Use](https://www.midlandcredit.com/terms-of-use/).

Continue

Terms of Use (TOU)
------------------

### Effective as of February 7, 2023

× Dismiss

### Consumer Testimonials

#### Learn more about what our consumers say about us
